

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Infrastructure Solution Engineer

7+ years of industry experience in managing AWS Public Cloud infrastructure and On-Premise datacenter virtualized infrastructure layer with high available and redundant design. Datacenter infra support on Compute virtualization stack. Expanded my scope onto enterprise-level infra architecture for domestic and global customers. **VMware Consultant & security** analyst with a wide range of VMware product support to global customers. Primarily onto AWS Operations and ESXi / vCenter upgrades, patch security compliance based on VMware best Advisories

CORE TECHNOLOGY SUPPORT

- AWS Cloud Services EC2,S3,VPC,CloudWatch,IAM,Auto Scaling,ELB,IGW, Route Table, NAT Gateway, AMI,VPC Endpoint Gateway & Interface Gateway, Security Group.
- VMware Specialist Esxi | Vcenter |
 VRops | VSphere Replication |
 VSAN.
- MS Windows Administration SCVMM 2012 & 2016 | Hyper–V 2012 & 2016 | Windows servers & Admin Center.
- Hardware Support HPE Proliant & Synergy 12000 Frames | Dell Poweredge Servers | Dell EMC OME for Hardware Firmware Compliance Management | Lenovo XClarity Controller & Administrator.
- Linux intermediate Support

Amarnath Antony

6

+919790681401



antonyamar14@gmail.com

Ochennai, India

EXPERIENCE

10/2021 - Current FIS Global | Chennai AWS & VMware Consultant

- Designing and Managing Public / Private cloud infrastructure on AWS using VPC, EC2, S3, Cloud Front, Cloud Watch, and Endpoint / Interface Gateway.
- · Worked with Amazon IAM console to create custom users and groups.
- Worked on configuring security groups, setting up Elastic IPs and autoscaling configuration.
- Using VPC flow log to monitor and track the incoming and outgoing traffic from Subnets, ENI & VPC.
- Responsible for creating VPC on AWS that supports DEV, TEST and PROD environments.
- Configured and managed various AWS Services including EC2, RDS, VPC, S3, Cloud Front and Route 53.
- Designed and implemented Security best practices at instance, subnet and VPC level to fortifying cloud infrastructure.
- Focus on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto scaling using AWS cloud formation.
- Created and maintained account policies & Roles in IAM, Security Groups and Access control lists.
- Installed and configured IGW. Route Tables for public facing subnets and NAT for private-facing subnets on AWS VPCs.
- Deployment of AWS systems with high scalability, availability, and faulttolerance.
- Serve as a tech spec in project planning and collaborate with the project manager to develop technical and architectural design strategies.
- Develop strong relationships b/w customers and cultivate solid trust in infrastructural architecture change design.
- Managing the central patching program for Esxi coordinating with the different support teams to onboard the ESXi into the central patching scope.
- Providing end-to-end planning to BAU team on Esxi patching & Hardware firmware upgrade plan based on recommended version from the support vendors.
- Governance in Vsphere infrastructure and maintaining security profile to avoid thread vulnerability. Managing Esxi host running in Vsphere environment with different marketproducts i:e HPE Proliant / Synergy / Simplivity , CISCO HyperFLex , Dell PowerEdge / OME etc

 HCI Product - HPE Simplivity nodeinter-datacenter replication & Nutanix on Dell EMC servers support.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

 Achievements , Best Innovation Silver Infosys IT Awards 2019 -2020

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Certified Solution Associate: Windows Server 2012 (MCSA)
- ITIL V4 Foundation

HOBBIES

- Swimming
- Roller Skating
- Reading Technology related blogs

12/2020 - 10/2021

Tata Consultancy Services | Chennai Information Technology Specialist

- Global Datacenter virtualization support. Providing End to End infrastructure design/planning/implementation and migration service.
- Managing different VMware / HPE Products to provide solutions and to meet the daily BAU. Participating in product vendor calls / leads techconsultant meet on behalf of TCS for continuous datacenter infrastructure service.
- A vast amount of experience in project transition planning / existing infrastructure expansion / operations process documents preparation and creating SOW to support team and end users. Adhering to ITIL compliance and also to on-demand supporting strategy.
- Creating process documents and SOP / standardization of Esxi patching across the global enterprise infra, in-result to reduce the overall vulnerability.

09/2018 - 11/2020

Infosys Ltd | Mysore

Senior System Engineer

- On-premise data center operations management, infrastructure as service support to global/domestic customers.
- Providing solutions for Tier 2 / Tier 3 data center design and migration.
 Virtualized infrastructure layer design ESXI / KVM & Hyper-v deployment and maintenance plan. HPE Synergy 12000 frame/ Simplivity installation strategy expand the system / Increasing available resource and merge into existing running infrastructure.
- Basic understanding of AWS precedents for cloud architecture Experience in management and operations of systems on AWS.
- Good knowledge of security concepts with practical experience in implementing security controls.
- · Knowledge regarding networking concepts such as DNS, Firewalls, and TCP/IP
- Identifying appropriate uses for the best practices of AWS operations

03/2016 - 09/2018

NTTDATA | Chennai

System Analyst

- Enhanced remote support for managing region- specific data center virtualization
- Design/deployment and management of entire compute model structure
- Compute model that includes procurement dealing, product comparison, analyzing features, cost- effective.
- Work experience in Windows Hyper-V environment managing 8node cluster configured in SCVMM.

EDUCATION

Aug 2011 to Apr 2015

Anna University - Dr.Sivanthi Aditanar College Of Engineering | Tiruchendur Bachelor of Engineering

LANGUAGES

Tamil: First Language

English: C1

Advanced